幾個世紀以來，我們研究了這個星球上許許多多變化萬千的物種…
…來幫助我們瞭解…
…生生不息的自然界如何運作
世界上數以千計的研究機構及其學者…
投注了許多努力、生產知識，分享在…
…數百萬的論文發表和研究著作中
便能輕易的找到這些資訊。
在這些資訊背後，大部分的數據…
…四處分散、不易取得…
這些原始數據若能進一步分析、利用且再重覆利用，
…也不易用來分析及重覆使用
而資料分析及重覆使用正是創造及增進知識必要的基礎。
您能夠想像：如果有更多人能夠找到…
…並能輕易地利用經過組織的資料…
…我們將能發掘出多少關於自然界的知識嗎？
全球生物多樣性資訊機構（GBIF）
是一個由各國政府及相關機構形成的網絡
它推動了資料的發表
並且讓全世界共享
讓生物多樣性的資訊
能夠無時無刻地在線上、從任何地點
提供給研究人員及公民大眾使用
In response to recommendations
from international agreements and conventions,
GBIF includes dozens of participating countries
and nearly 2,000 publishers,
bringing together a global scale data infrastructure for the natural world
that informs the sustainable use of biodiversity
and contributes to improving people’s quality of life.
GBIF allows you to share the data that you capture,
organize, standardize and publish,
contributing to research, education and decision-making
and expanding the knowledge we have about our environment.
Data publishers can choose the type of use and attribution
that they want for their data
and receive public recognition for their contributions.
GBIF also makes it possible
for any citizen of the world, including you,
to access all the free and open data
published through the network’s data portals.
The nodes from each one of the participating countries
advise and work with organizations
through all phases of the data publishing process
to guarantee high-quality data, that are open and accessible.
We want you to be part of GBIF,
so that together we can build a sustainable future
in which biodiversity information is free and universally available
to science and society.
To learn more about how to become part of
this global biodiversity network,
請造訪 www.gbif.org/zh-tw